

# **Mohammed Emad Omer**

## Full Stack Developer





moemad191@gmail.com

Well-qualified Full Stack Developer familiar with a wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements. Handles any part of the process with ease. Collaborative team player with excellent technical abilities offering 10 years of related experience.



#### **Technical Profile**



- HTML
- CSS
- Tailwind
- JavaScript
- ES6
- ES2017
- JQurey
- TypeSccript
- React js
- Webpack
- MongoDB
- RESTful API
- mongoosejs
- NodeJS
- ExpressJS
- RxJS
- Redux
- Postman
- Firebase
- Heroku
- UML
- ER Diagrams
- GitHub
- Agile scrum



## **Competencies**



API design knowledge



CSS proficiency



JavaScript programming

Operational analysis

Database programming

Database management software

HTML expertise

React is framework proficiency



## **Work History**

2014-07 - Current

#### Full Stack Developer

Ruknan for Public Relations, Riyadh

- Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Participated in requirements gathering to solidify prerequisites and determine best technical solution to meet business needs.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Coordinated efficient large-scale software deployments.
- Used SQL/No-SQL to develop and manage databases.
- Adjusted design parameters to incorporate new features.
- Developed functional databases, applications and servers to support websites on back-end.
- Worked with back-end developers to design APIs.
- Finishing development of three important sites using MERN stack

#### 2013-06 - 2013-08

#### PHP Web Developer

ANO Consultancy, Khartoum

- Created web applications and components using PHP programming language.
- Developed back-end components to connect application with mysql database.
- Wrote server-side and client-side code for Personal Expense
   Management System projects using PHP, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

## .NET Software Developer, Full Stack

Mehwer Agency for Travelling and tourism, Khartoum

- Developing commission affiliate tickets system
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- Participated in requirements gathering to solidify prerequisites and determine best technical solution to meet business needs.

#### 2012-02 - 2013-02

2013-02 - 2013-04

## Programming Tutor

The National Program for UNESCO Clubs in Sudan, Khartoum

- Planned lessons for allotted time to strengthen weak subjects and build skills.
- Collaborated with students to complete homework assignments, identify lagging skills and correct weaknesses.

- Teaching students programming skills using C++.
- Teaching students website designing skills using HTMLCSS.
- Supported students with helpful study habits and exam strategies.
- Coached and mentored less-experienced tutors to observe and measure outcomes



## **Education**

2008-10 - 2012-11

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

BAYAN COLLEGE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY - Khartoum, Sudan



# **Accomplishments**

- A certificate of thanks and appreciation from Ruknan for public relations Administration for my efforts in setting plans, distributing business, and following up the workflow
- Collaborated with a team of 4 in the development of a Media monitoring website.
- Getting thanks from one of the clients of the Ruknan For public relations (Anti-Corruption Commission) For my efforts to train the authority's employees to use the Media monitoring website.